Me and my girlfriend
我和我的女友
The two of us have been living apart in two places
我们两个人一直分居两地
I don't even have a chance to introduce you to them.
我什至没有机会向你介绍他们。
Moreover
而且
Ever since I worked under your hand
自从我在你手下工作以来
I experienced the feasting and feasting of Shanghai with you
我和你一起体验了上海的灯红酒绿
A man
一个男人
This can never make life
这永远无法让生活
Missing some possibilities
缺少一些可能性
OK
好的
understand
理解
Which bus did your girlfriend take?
你女朋友坐哪路公交车？
What time did you arrive?
你什么时候抵达的？
Where did it come from?
它从哪里来的？
Wuhan
武汉
From Wuhan to Shanghai via Xuzhou Tongshan
From Wuhan to Shanghai via Xuzhou Tongshan
429 degrees
429度
2:40 p.m.
下午 2:40
What time did you pick her up?
你什么时候来接她的？
It's past three o'clock
已经三点多了
She arrived at two forty
她于两点四十分到达
Why did you pick her up after three o'clock?
你为什么三点以后才来接她？
Jiaping said he would pick me up at exit A
家平说他会在A出口接我
But it’s not like he doesn’t know
但他又不是不知道
I'm blind
我瞎了
Where can I find the exit gate?
我在哪里可以找到出口？
How many times have I told her
我跟她说过多少次了
If you don’t know the way, ask more people.
如果你不认识路，就多问人。
Then what can I do if she doesn't ask me?
那如果她不问我怎么办？
Then you
然后你
Where have you been all this time?
你去哪儿了这么长的时间？
I've always been at Exit A
我一直在A出口
Around Yamashita Assassination Clinic
山下暗杀诊所周边
you haven't been
你还没有去过
No
不
What am I doing there?
我在那里做什么？
Have you come to Shanghai to find him before?
你以前来过上海找过他吗？
No
不
Why do you come here now?
你为什么现在来这里？
Tell me as quickly as possible
尽快告诉我
What are your specific circumstances in Wuhan?
您在武汉的具体情况如何？
And living habits
还有生活习惯
Also remember what I told you
还记得我告诉过你的话
She
她
I just think the work in Wuhan is too boring
我只是觉得武汉的工作太无聊了
There is no future
没有未来
There happened to be an aunt in Shanghai
恰好上海有一个阿姨
Just want to say
只是想说
Come and see Shanghai
来上海看看吧
big city
大城市
There's a lot to be done
还有很多事情要做
Actually there is another reason
其实还有一个原因
Just come and look at me
过来看看我
What's your girlfriend's job?
你女朋友的工作是什么？
A division under the Ministry of Finance
财政部下属司
What chamber
什么室
accounting office
会计师事务所
Since you plan to live in Shanghai permanently
由于您打算永久居住在上海
Where is the luggage?
行李在哪里？
Why don't you even have any luggage?
为什么连行李都没有？
Too much luggage
行李太多
How can I hold it?
我怎样才能握住它？
Three big boxes of bare clothes
三大箱裸衣服
I must be lucky by water
我一定是幸运的水
It will arrive in a few days
几天后就会到货
Do you know what he does in Shanghai?
你知道他在上海做什么吗？
Isn't it Taihe Trading Company?
不是太和商贸公司吗？
trading house
贸易公司
Then it must be a business
那么一定是一门生意
He showed off to me
他向我炫耀
What kind of section chief is he?
他是个什么样的科长？
Did I tell you the address of the business office?
我有告诉过你营业厅的地址吗？
I said it
我说了
Jisi Feier Road, Huxi District, Shanghai
Jisi Feier Road, Huxi District, Shanghai
No. 26
26号
how to contact you
如何联系你
Call up
给...打电话
write a letter
写一封信
What is the switchboard phone number of the business bank?
工商银行的总机电话号码是多少？
explain
解释
I don't know this
我不知道这个
He called me all the time
他一直打电话给我
Men
男士
Be proactive
主动
her phone
她的电话
I always call the Ministry of Finance switchboard.
我总是拨打财政部总机。
Then transfer to their department
然后调到他们部门
68333 to 197
68333转197
remember remember
记得记得
Oh My God
我的天啊
Where are you and Miss Zuo?
你和左小姐在哪里？
When did we meet
我们什么时候认识的
You have to ask this too
这个你也得问
Autumn 1936
1936 年秋
Nanjing
南京
We are in the autumn of the 25th year of the Republic of China
我们正值民国二十五年的秋天
Met in October
十月相识
Where was your first date?
你第一次约会是在哪里？
Zhonghuamen Nei Confucius Temple
Zhonghuamen Nei Confucius Temple
movies to watch
要看的电影
crossroads
十字路口
who
WHO
Don't, don't, don't
别别别别
Never let go
绝不放手
Are you scared to death?
你怕得要死吗？
you police
你警察
When shooting at our patriotic students
当我们向爱国学生开枪时
Why not afraid
为什么不害怕
No, I'm not a police officer
不，我不是警察
I also participated in the patriotic parade
我也参加了爱国游行
I knocked out a policeman
我打晕了一个警察
changed his clothes
换了衣服
And stole his car
并偷了他的车
What I want is to take all these things away
我想要的就是把这些东西全部拿走
Why should I believe you?
我为什么要相信你？
look
看
I also have a red armband
我也有红袖章
Same as you
和你一样
But many classmates died
但很多同学都死了
It's easy to get an armband like this
这样的臂章很容易获得
no
不
Don't be nervous
别紧张
you have my gun
你有我的枪
facing me
面对我
Then I'll go find the latch
然后我就去找门闩
Don't, don't, don't
别别别别
Don't get mad
别生气
Where did you throw the latch?
你把门闩扔哪儿了？
no
不
You are hurt
你受伤了
so
所以
I'd better help you stop bleeding first.
我最好先帮你止血。
ok
好的
Don't, don't, don't
别别别别
Don't face me
别面对我
sit down
坐下
Slow down, slow down, slow down
慢点，慢点，慢点
Let me take a look
让我看一看
What school do you go to
你就读什么学校
south nanjing
南京南
Finance College
金融学院
Bear with it
忍受它
What's your name
你叫什么名字
Zuo Shuangtao
Zuo Shuangtao
My classmates all call me Guoguo
我的同学都叫我果果
Guoguo
Guoguo
That's a nice name
这是个好名字
Be patient, be patient
要有耐心，要有耐心
alright
好吧
But you you
但你你
Why do you have grenades?
为什么你有手榴弹？
Our parade was shot at
我们的游行遭到枪击
The organizer of the march was seriously injured
游行组织者受重伤
The grenade he gave me
他给我的手榴弹
He also told me this address
他还告诉我这个地址
Said there was very important information here
说这里有非常重要的信息
We cannot fall into the hands of the reactionary police
我们不能落入反动警察手中
But
但
The two of us are spending time here
我们两个人在这里消磨时光
It's not a problem either
这也不是问题
The police will chase you soon
警察很快就会追捕你
Otherwise
否则
Do you believe what I say
你相信我说的话吗
When I say loosen up, just loosen up.
当我说放松时，就放松吧。
Don't be afraid
别害怕
Just treat it like the two of us watching a movie
就像我们两个人看电影一样
Have you seen Crossroads?
你看过十字路口吗？
Are you ready?
你准备好了吗？
three
三
two
二
one
一
loose
松动的
Oh my god
我的天啊
wait for me a while
等我一会儿
Let me deal with it first
让我先处理一下
Go, go, go
去！去！去
Walk
走
What should I do with this thing?
我该怎么处理这个东西？
Leave it alone
不要管它
Leave the rest to me
剩下的交给我
I think it's almost the same
我认为几乎是一样的
Zhao An, this bastard
赵安这个混蛋
No big deal
没什么大不了
I have to struggle until now
我必须奋斗到现在
correct
正确的
I heard Zhao An say
我听赵安说
When he picked you up at the train station
当他去火车站接你的时候
Miss Zuo said
左小姐说
Are you going to Wing On Mall?
你要去永安商场吗？
But the direction you are going
但你要去的方向
It's southwest
是西南方向
Wing On Shopping Center is in the north
北边是永安购物中心
Did she lie?
她撒谎了吗？
Miss Zuo
Miss Zuo
You said you came to Shanghai from Wuhan
你说你从武汉来上海
That's right
这是正确的
can i have a look at your ticket
我可以看一下你的票吗
She did lie
她确实撒谎了
Biased a bit
有点偏激
What's this
这是什么
sachet
香囊
Never seen it
没见过
never seen it
从没见过
good smell
好闻
where did it come from
它从哪里来的
Bought at the train station
火车站买的
This sachet is very good
这个香包非常好
I would also like
我也想要
Love is difficult
爱情很难
Oh My God
我的天啊
Why don't you read it out?
你为什么不读出来呢？
Can you save some face for me?
你能给我留点面子吗？
Are you ashamed?
你羞耻吗？
My girlfriend finally came here
我女朋友终于来了
We haven't seen each other for so long
我们已经很久没见面了
Who can think of going to the mall, right?
谁会想到去商场，对吧？
dry firewood
干柴
What are you laughing laughing
你笑什么笑
you boy
你小子
Wouldn't it be over if you told me earlier?
如果你早点告诉我，事情不就结束了吗？
Team Leader Zhao
赵组长
Have you finished asking all the questions?
你问完所有问题了吗？
I still want to take advantage of the dawn
我还想趁着黎明
Going out for shopping
外出购物
Miss Zuo, don't worry
左小姐，别担心
I want to introduce someone to you
我想向你介绍一个人
please come here
请来这里
Fangfang
Fangfang
Captain Zhao
Captain Zhao
What do you want me to do?
你想要我做什么？
Beautiful again
又美丽了
Thanks
谢谢
I want to ask you something
我想问你点事儿
are you
你是
I really like Chen Jiaping
我真的很喜欢陈家平
What for?
做什么的？
I'm not allowed to like people yet
我还没有被允许喜欢别人
Very lenient
非常宽容
It's not not allowed
这不是不允许的
care
关心
Are you concerned about the living conditions of your employees?
您关心员工的生活条件吗？
What about him?
那么他呢？
Does Jiaping like you too?
家平也喜欢你吗？
That's natural
那是自然的
Does Captain Zhao think we are a good match?
赵队长觉得我们很般配吗？
a good match
一场很好的比赛
What a perfect match
多么完美的搭配
such a pity
真可惜
I'm just better than my family
我只是比我的家人更好
How old are you?
你今年多大？
Fangfang
Fangfang
What age is this?
这是什么年纪了？
Popular sister-brother romance
流行的姐弟恋
Be confident
自信点
When will we be invited to a wedding banquet?
我们什么时候会被邀请参加婚宴？
Eat wedding candy
吃喜糖
Then it depends on Jia Ping
那就看贾平了
When did you propose to me?
你什么时候向我求婚的？
Soon
很快
Miss Zuo
Miss Zuo
I don't want to ruin your relationship
我不想破坏你们的关系
Actually, I'm here to help you
事实上，我是来帮助你的
how to help me
如何帮助我
I tell the truth
我实话实说
I didn't doubt you
我没有怀疑你
You are a weak woman
你是一个软弱的女人
Looks so beautiful
看起来很漂亮
How could it be related to Yamashita's assassination?
怎么会和山下遇刺有关系呢？
our real purpose
我们真正的目的
To investigate Chen Jiaping
To investigate Chen Jiaping
Why investigate Chen Jiaping?
为什么要调查陈家平？
Let me tell you this
让我告诉你这个
Chen Jiaping appeared at the train station
陈家平现身火车站
If I didn’t make an appointment with you to pick you up
如果我没有约你去接你
Then he is very likely
那么他很有可能
Related to Yamashita's assassination
与山下刺杀有关
or with another
或与另一个
Related to a case involving underground organizations of the Chinese Communist Party
涉及中共地下组织案件
you just heard
你刚刚听到
Chen Jiaping emotionally
陈家平情绪激动
Not very dedicated to you
不太专心为你
You don't need to protect him, right?
你没必要保护他吧？
tell me the truth
告诉我真相
are you
你是
I just happened to meet Chen Jiaping at the train station
我刚好在火车站遇见了陈家平
Then you were used by him
然后你就被他利用了
Miss Zuo
Miss Zuo
if you tell me the truth
如果你告诉我真相
I'll let you go shopping right away
我马上让你去购物
okay
好的
I'll show this to the Japanese
我要把这个给日本人看
It should be almost fine
应该差不多就好了
You can go back
你可以回去了
What's wrong
怎么了
Chen Jiaping
Chen Jiaping
You are so interesting
你真有趣
Forget it if you lie to Zhao An
骗赵安就算了
You still lied to me
你还是骗了我
What did I lie to you about?
我骗你什么了？
You're still pretending
你还在假装
Zuo Shuangtao recognized it
左双涛认出了
She hasn't contacted you for a long time.
她已经很久没有联系你了。
I came to Shanghai to visit my aunt.
我来上海看望我的姨妈。
I happened to bump into you at the train station
我在火车站碰巧遇见了你
You have to ask her
你得问她
Said you picked her up
说你接她了
Let her cooperate with you
让她配合你
You go to the train station
你去火车站
What on earth are you going to do?
你到底要做什么？
Don’t tell Zhao An
别告诉赵安
Can't you tell me?
你不能告诉我吗？
I don't know what you are going to do?
我不知道你要做什么？
Just this little deal
就这点小事
Private purchase and sale
私人购买和销售
Are you the only one doing this in the business?
您是业内唯一这样做的人吗？
What can you do if you tell me?
如果你告诉我你能做什么？
If you have something to do, I'll take care of it for you.
如果你有什么事情要做，我会为你处理的。
what are you afraid of
你怕什么呢
You may not understand the situation yet
你可能还不了解情况
Your things are trivial
你的事情都是小事
The story of Zuo Shuangtao
左双涛的故事
Big
大的
When Yamashita was killed
山下被杀的时候
Zuo Shuangtao is within the range of activities
左双涛在活动范围内
Decide her now
现在就决定她
An associate of the assassin
凶手的同伙
fellow assassin
刺客同伙
I tell you
我告诉你
Don't let this old relationship
别让这段旧情
Let Zuo Shuangtao take advantage of you
Let Zuo Shuangtao take advantage of you
tell me the truth
告诉我真相
You don’t know Zuo Shuangtao
你不认识左双涛
I happened to meet you at the train station
我碰巧在火车站遇见你
She asked you
她问你
take her out
带她出去
Coordinate her
协调她
Yes or no
是还是不是
Communist Party associates
共产党员
Let me tell you the truth
让我告诉你真相
you say
你说
My truth is
我的真相是
Luo Guanqun, you are a bastard.
Luo Guanqun, you are a bastard.
I have treated you as my big brother for so many years
这么多年我一直把你当作我的大哥
Now you turn around and falsely confess to me.
现在你却转身向我虚假告白。
I tell you
我告诉你
I went to the train station to pick up my girlfriend
我去火车站接我女朋友
She came to Shanghai to find me
她来上海找我
I say this today
我今天说这个
She said so too
她也这么说
because that's the truth
因为这就是事实
Team Leader Zhao
赵组长
I want to go shopping
我想去购物
OK
好的
I'll send you a car
我给你送一辆车
Need not
不需要
Jia Ping will take me there
贾平会带我去那里
If he is really with that Lu Fangfang
如果他真的和那个陆芳芳在一起的话
have what
有什么
Of course I won't let him go
我当然不会放开他
But what you said is all nonsense
但你说的都是废话
I'm here to see Chen Jiaping
我是来看陈家平的
Jia Ping went to the train station to pick me up.
家平去火车站接我。
I'm not in the mood
我心情不好
I keep repeating these two sentences to you.
我不断地向你重复这两句话。
Do you believe it or not?
你信不信？
If you don’t believe it, take me away
不信的话就带我走吧
Take it away quickly
赶紧拿走
Don't
不
Hurry up
赶快
Come on, come on, stop grinding
来吧，来吧，别磨了
You are really
你真是
Chen Jiaping, where are you?
陈家平，你在哪里？
come out
出来
Chen Jiaping
Chen Jiaping
What's wrong
怎么了
Jiaping
Jiaping
Please give me a good explanation
请给我一个好的解释
What's going on between you and Lu Fangfang?
你和吕芳芳之间到底是怎么回事？
no
不
You can just interrogate both of us.
你可以审问我们俩。
Why did you drag Lu Fangfang into this?
为什么要把陆芳芳也拉进来？
Misunderstand
误解
It must have been done by Zhao An
肯定是赵安干的
He fooled me all
他骗了我所有人
Did you hear that?
你听到了吗？
Misunderstand
误解
It's not what you think
这不是你想的那样
elder brother
哥哥
That Zuo Shuangtao will not be tried.
那左双涛不会受审。
Not without trial
并非未经审判
Examine in another way
用另一种方式检查
I know Luo Guanqun
I know Luo Guanqun
That crappy thing doesn't work
那个蹩脚的东西不起作用
How's the assassin doing?
刺客怎么样了？
Not dead yet
还没死
But I can't last much longer.
但我撑不了多久了。
What about the cold dew?
那寒露呢？
On the way, almost there
路上，快到了
Find Gao Fang
Find Gao Fang
His skills are put to use
他的技能得到了运用
clear
清除
I'm going to report to Chief Kimura
我要去向木村队长汇报
Next
下一个
It's my turn to sing this play
轮到我来唱这出戏了
Isn't this just a formality?
这不只是一个形式吗？
do not mind
别在意
Shanghai beach is fun
上海滩很好玩
It’s time to eat and go shopping
是时候吃饭和逛街了
what do you need
你需要什么
Tell me
告诉我
You got it, you Lao Luo
懂了，老罗
How can you think of that?
你怎么能想到这一点？
Also shopping
还购物
Still eating
还在吃
Let's go have a meal
我们去吃饭吧
Walk
走
Still eating?
还在吃吗？
Have you made it clear about Lu Fangfang?
陆芳芳的事你说清楚了吗？
It's okay
没关系
misunderstanding misunderstanding
误解 误解
This is all a misunderstanding
这一切都是误会
Huayou Building at night
华友大厦夜景
my treat
我请客
you two
你们俩
No one is allowed to leave
任何人都不得离开
Zhao An, what else do you want to do?
赵安，你还想做什么？
There is new evidence
有新证据
Continue to be investigated
继续调查
What new evidence do you have?
你有什么新证据？
Chief Kimura’s order
木村队长的命令
It's so late
这么晚了
What the hell is Zhao An up to?
赵安到底想干什么？
Zhao An
Zhao An
What is this?
这是什么？
german guy
德国佬
Hello Miss Hanlu
韩璐小姐你好
You are looking for me
你在找我
What do you want to ask?
你想问什么？
I heard you were in danger at the train station today
我听说你今天在火车站遇到危险
yes
是的
What's wrong
怎么了
I heard that there was a man
听说有一个男人
I pushed you away in time
我及时把你推开
Just to save you from disaster
只为救你脱离灾难
right
正确的
that person
那个人
do you know
你知道吗
do not know
不知道
Look, is it him?
你看，是他吗？
I don't quite understand what you mean
我不太明白你的意思
Colonel Takeo Yamashita
山下武夫大佐
Miss Hanlu
韩璐小姐
I must know him
我必须认识他
he is my friend
他是我的朋友
I heard that when I was in Manchuria
我在满洲的时候就听说了
Colonel Takeo Yamashita
山下武夫大佐
Several films have been arranged
已安排好几部影片
Movies produced by Manying allow you to act
曼影出品的电影让你演戏
You two have a deep relationship
你们两个关系很深
What exactly do you want to ask?
您到底想问什么？
Colonel Yamashita Takeo today
今天的山下武夫大佐
stabbed at train station
在火车站被刺伤
dead
死的
do you know
你知道吗
Death under the mountain
死在山下
This person’s name is Chen Jiaping
这个人的名字叫陈家平
I suspect he has something to do with the assassination
我怀疑他与暗杀事件有关
You are the key witness
你是关键证人
I
我
he insisted
他坚持说
He has been at the exit of the train station
他已经在火车站出口了
Didn't go near the area where Yamashita was assassinated.
没有靠近山下被刺杀的地方。
But the scene of your assassination
但你被刺杀的场景
Very close to the scene of Yamashita's assassination
离山下刺杀现场很近
If he is the one who saves you
如果他是拯救你的人
That proves that Chen Jiaping lied
这证明陈家平撒谎了
I think of course you won't protect anyone
我想你当然不会保护任何人
The murderer who assassinated Yamashita Takeo?
刺杀山下武夫的凶手？
of course not
当然不是
the person who saved you
救了你的人
It's him, right?
是他吧？
yes
是的
The person who saved me was Chen Jiaping
救我的人是陈家平
Jiaping
Jiaping
You don’t have to tell me in a hurry
你不必着急告诉我
why do you lie
你为什么撒谎
Let's listen to the next one
我们来听下一首
your name
你的名字
Feng Qi
Feng Qi
Pull out one of his nails
拔掉他的一根指甲
your name
你的名字
Li Li Daxuan
Li Li Daxuan
Who sent you to assassinate Takeo Yamashita?
是谁派你去刺杀山下武夫的？
group organization
团体组织
What organization
什么组织
I only know that we are anti-Japanese
我只知道我们是抗日的
Accept orders from superiors
接受上级命令
No other questions are allowed
不允许提出其他问题
The one who ran away
那个逃跑的人
Are we in the same group as you?
我们和你是同一组的吗？
yes
是的
I know him
我认识他
we are in the same group
我们在同一组
What's his name
他叫什么名字
His name is A Kun
他的名字叫阿坤
Except Akun
除了阿昆
Are there any other accomplices?
还有其他同伙吗？
there is none left
已所剩无几
Pull out nails again
再次拔掉指甲
Feng Qi
Feng Qi
look
看
let him see
让他看看
This woman named Zuo Shuangtao
This woman named Zuo Shuangtao
do you know
你知道吗
Is she on your side?
她站在你这边吗？
take all his nails
拿走他所有的指甲
All pulled out
全部拉出来了
don't want
不想要
I said
我说
I know her
我认识她
we are in the same group
我们在同一组
Chen Jiaping
Chen Jiaping
you lied
你撒谎
Miss Double Peach
双桃小姐
You lied too
你也撒谎了
Confessions of Daxuan and Hanlu
大轩与寒露的自白
It explains everything
它解释了一切
Zhao An
Zhao An
I'll leave this matter to you.
这件事就交给你了。
etc.
ETC。
What else do you have to say
你还有什么要说的
can i listen to it again
我可以再听一遍吗
good
好的
listen again
再听一遍
Manager Na Luo
Manager Na Luo
I feel sorry for you and listen carefully again
我为你感到难过，再仔细听一遍
etc.
ETC。
what are you doing
你在干什么
Captain Zhao
Captain Zhao
Can I do it?
我可以做吗？
Do you know
你知道吗
Okay
好的
Hello Miss Hanlu
韩璐小姐你好
You are looking for me
你在找我
What do you want to ask?
你想问什么？
I heard you were in danger at the train station today
我听说你今天在火车站遇到危险
yes
是的
What's wrong
怎么了
I heard that there was a man
听说有一个男人
I pushed you away in time
我及时把你推开
Just to save you from disaster
只为救你脱离灾难
right
正确的
that person
那个人
do you know
你知道吗
yes
是的
The person who saved me was Chen Jiaping
救我的人是陈家平
Aren't you okay?
你还好吗？
Don't mess up
别搞砸了
yes
是的
The person who saved me was Chen Jiaping
救我的人是陈家平
Captain Zhao
Captain Zhao
Zuo Shuangtao's recording
Zuo Shuangtao's recording
I also want to hear it again
我也想再听一遍
casual
随意的
your name
你的名字
Li Li Daxuan
Li Li Daxuan
The one who ran away
那个逃跑的人
Are we in the same group as you?
我们和你是同一组的吗？
What's his name
他叫什么名字
yes
是的
I know him
我认识他
we are in the same group
我们在同一组
His name is A Kun
他的名字叫阿坤
Captain Zhao
Captain Zhao
You're so good at joking
你很会开玩笑
What am I kidding you?
我开什么玩笑？
good recording
录音效果好
Why did you edit it?
你为什么要编辑它？
has been edited
已编辑
do you have evidence
你有证据吗
are you kidding me
你在开玩笑吧
Let me analyze it
我来分析一下
Lao Luo
Lao Luo
Do you hear the sound of water dripping in the background?
您听到背景中水滴的声音吗？
Water leaks in recording studio
录音室漏水
It's normal to use a basin to connect it
用盆连接就正常了
Yes, it's normal
是的，这很正常
listen again
再听一遍
Listen carefully
仔细听
yes
是的
The person who saved me was Chen Jiaping
救我的人是陈家平
I didn't hear it
我没听到
First half of recording
录音前半部分
The sound of water dripping is indeed uniform
水滴的声音确实均匀
But why did you reach the last sentence?
但为什么会到最后一句话呢？
The sound of water dripping became faster and slower
水滴的声音越来越快越来越慢
Do you know why
你知道为什么吗
Is the person who saved you Chen Jiaping?
救你的人是陈家平吗？
Miss Hanlu
韩璐小姐
I am your movie fan. Please sign it for me.
我是你的电影迷。请帮我签名。
no
不
save my person
拯救我的人
Not Chen Jiaping
Not Chen Jiaping
besides
除了
Don't rush to explain
不要急于解释
Lao Luo
Lao Luo
Let’s listen to Li Daxuan’s conversation again
我们再听听李大轩的对话
yes
是的
I know him
我认识他
we are in the same group
我们在同一组
His name is A Kun
他的名字叫阿坤
remember this sentence
记住这句话
I know him
我认识他
we are in the same group
我们在同一组
Listen to the second half of his part
听他的后半部分
This woman named Zuo Shuangtao
This woman named Zuo Shuangtao
do you know
你知道吗
Is she on your side?
她站在你这边吗？
take all his nails
拿走他所有的指甲
All pulled out
全部拉出来了
don't want
不想要
I said
我说
I know him
我认识他
we are in the same group
我们在同一组
Captain Zhao
Captain Zhao
a word
一个字
Li Daxuan said it twice
李大轩说了两遍
They all coughed in the same place.
他们都在同一个地方咳嗽。
Do you think it's a coincidence?
你认为这是巧合吗？
I don't think
我不认为
but i think
但我觉得
Captain Zhao used one sentence twice.
赵队长一句话用了两次。
I do not know her
我不认识她
died
死了
play high
玩得高
Can it be handled?
可以处理吗？
Don't worry, it's no problem
别担心，没问题
Zhao An
Zhao An
You are so audacious
你真大胆
Jia Ping is one of his own
贾平是他自己的一员
Zuo Shuangtao is Jia Ping’s girlfriend
Zuo Shuangtao is Jia Ping’s girlfriend
Also considered one of our own
也被认为是我们自己的一员
You use such despicable means
你使用如此卑鄙的手段
Trick them
欺骗他们
The same routine that played badly before
同样的套路，之前打得不好
is yours
是你的
Don't blame it all on me
别把这一切都归咎于我
You're talking nonsense
你在胡说八道
I command you
我命令你
Release me immediately
立即释放我
immediately
立即地
Can you go?
你可以去吗？
Let's go
我们走吧
why did you leave
你为什么离开
Dining at Huayou Building
华友大厦餐饮
my treat
我请客
my eldest brother
我的大哥
Miss Zuo
Miss Zuo
I didn't take good care of myself today
我今天没照顾好自己
Both you and Jia Ping were frightened.
你和家平都害怕了。
Come on, come on, I'll punish myself with a drink
来吧来吧，我要喝一杯来惩罚自己
Punish yourself with a drink
用喝酒惩罚自己
Anyway, that Zhao An won’t be able to dance for long.
无论如何，那个赵安跳舞的时间不会太长了。
Thirty-six thunder boss fights autumn
三十六雷霆boss战秋
I'll settle the score with him again in the future.
以后我再跟他算账。
I won’t talk about this today
我今天不谈这个
Take this bite and I'll respect you again
咬一口，我会再次尊重你
frightened
受惊
Jia Ping told me before
家平之前跟我说过
Work in a Sino-Japanese joint venture firm
在中日合资企业工作
I thought
我想
He is making money and enjoying happiness
他一边赚钱一边享受幸福
I did not expect
我没有期待
Daqing is a devil's cave
大庆是魔窟
yes
是的
There are no outsiders here either
这里也没有外人
I might as well tell you straight
我不妨直接告诉你
We work for the Japanese
我们为日本人工作
Beat, kill, kill
打、杀、杀
The matter of using knives and guns
使用刀和枪的问题
That's inevitable
这是不可避免的
Got it
知道了
It turns out to be a traitor's den
原来是叛徒窝点
Miss Zuo is very outspoken.
左小姐很直言不讳。
I like
我喜欢
By the way, Miss Zuo
顺便说一句，左小姐
I heard Jia Ping say
我听贾平说
You come to Shanghai
你来上海
Are you interested in finding a job?
您有兴趣找工作吗？
Have you thought about it?
你想过吗？
No idea yet
还不知道
I will decide after visiting my aunt
我会在拜访我的阿姨之后再决定
Where does your aunt live?
你阿姨住在哪里？
Yu Gongguan
Yu Gongguan
where
在哪里
Mr. Yu Shanren's residence
Mr. Yu Shanren's residence
Working as a servant there
在那里当仆人
My aunt is the eldest wife of Mr. Yu Shanren
我的姨妈是于善人先生的大夫人
Zheng Yumei
Zheng Yumei
Yeah
是的
But she's not my aunt
但她不是我阿姨
She's my mother's cousin
她是我母亲的表弟
Mr. Yu
Mr. Yu
That's the chairman of Sanbei Ferry Port Company.
那是三北轮渡港公司董事长。
Another famous financial tycoon
另一位著名金融大亨
He is also the president of Shanghai General Chamber of Commerce
彼亦担任上海总商会会长
Even the Japanese have to look up to him.
就连日本人也不得不仰视他。
Chen Jiaping
Chen Jiaping
Your girlfriend
你女朋友
The background is quite amazing
背景相当惊人
Why don’t you make a toast quickly?
你为什么不快点干杯呢？
Come on
快点
Miss Zuo, here’s a toast to you
左小姐，敬你一杯
I go to the bathroom
我去卫生间
Excuse me for a while
请原谅我一会儿
good
好的
Come on, come on, let me drink for her
来来来，我给她喝一杯
I drink for her I drink for her
我为她喝酒 我为她喝酒
Chen Jiaping
Chen Jiaping
You did it on purpose, right?
你是故意的吧？
What's wrong
怎么了
Your girlfriend is my backer
你女朋友是我的靠山
You didn't tell me either
你也没告诉我
Didn’t I just know this?
我不是才知道这个吗？
Mr. Nayu stamped his foot
那由先生跺着脚
The beach in Shanghai is shaking
上海的海滩在震动
I wish I had known she had this connection
我希望我知道她有这种联系
What am I doing with you?
我和你在一起做什么？
you didn't lie to me
你没有骗我
When did I lie to you?
我什么时候骗过你了？
Then I have to toast you
那我得为你干杯
Come on
快点
Come, come, come
怎样怎样怎样
Big brother
大哥
Talk about something serious
谈论一些严肃的事情
After Yamashita was poisoned
山下中毒后
Sent to Ci'an Hospital
被送往慈安医院
Got another shot
又拍了一张
Even one of his security guards died.
甚至他的一名保安也死了。
I say this
我说这个
It's cruel enough
已经够残忍的了
The car is poisoned
车子中毒了
After getting out of the car, I refilled my gun.
下车后，我给枪重新装满子弹。
You said this was done by the military commander?
你说这是军统做的？
It was the CCP that did it
都是中共干的
I think it's the military
我认为这是军队
Why
为什么
What do you think?
你怎么认为？
After Yamashita was poisoned
山下中毒后
I still need to refill my gun when I get to Shanghai.
到了上海我还得给枪补气。
That would not only cost his life
这不仅会让他付出生命的代价
I also heard
我也听说
They are on Yamashita Takeo
他们在山下武夫
Said there was a secret letter from the military commander
说有军统的密信
But the strange thing is
但奇怪的是
Put it in the bag at the foot of the mountain
放在山脚下的包里
The secret letter was not found either.
那封密信也没有找到。
You need to check it carefully
你需要仔细检查一下
arrive
到达
Arrangements are here
安排在这里
In order to express my apology to you, Zhao An
为了向您表达歉意，赵安
I'll arrange for you to stay here tonight
今晚我会安排你住在这里
You guys take a good rest
你们好好休息
It won’t be too late to go to Yu’s house tomorrow
明天去于家也不晚
Okay, I won’t bother you anymore.
好吧，我不再打扰你了。
Hot, hot
热热
What's so hot about?
什么事这么火爆？
Half of my life was scared to death
半辈子都被吓死了
Even if your life is gone, you still have to be warm with me.
就算你的命没了，你也要和我温暖。
Go! Go! Go
去！去！去
Gone
走了
Walk slowly, walk slowly
慢慢走，慢慢走
This young couple
这对年轻夫妇
do you think something is wrong
你觉得有什么问题吗
No
不
What's wrong?
怎么了？
What a coincidence
多么巧合
Chen Jiaping suddenly had a girlfriend
陈家平突然有女朋友了
All at the train station
全部在火车站
Yamashita was assassinated
山下被暗杀
There are also traitors from the Chinese Communist Party
还有中共的汉奸
It's all such a coincidence
这一切都是那么的巧合
What a coincidence
多么巧合
There must be something fishy
一定有什么猫腻
Then I'll check it out
然后我会检查一下
No
不
Zhao An will check it out
赵安去看看
Let's wait and see what happens
让我们拭目以待，看看会发生什么
Chief Chen, please come inside
陈局长请进
You go
你去
good
好的
let's go
我们走吧
I close
我关上
good
好的
Chen Jiaping, let me ask you
陈家平，我问你一下
why do you want to fake
你为什么要假装
Why are you pretending that you still love me?
为什么你还要假装你还爱我？
Actually
实际上
You've changed your mind, haven't you?
你已经改变主意了，不是吗？
I'm not pretending
我不是假装
She's just being sentimental
她只是感性而已
Don't listen to her nonsense, okay?
别听她胡说八道好吗？
Self-motivated
自我激励
I think one slap can't make a sound, right?
我想一巴掌打不出声音吧？
I tell you
我告诉你
Don't quarrel with me
别跟我吵架
I've had enough trouble this day
我这一天已经受够了麻烦
I'm still annoyed
我还是很生气
If I had known I would never come to Shanghai
早知道我就不会来上海了
I thought I could buy foreign goods by taking the train
我以为坐火车就可以买外国货
The results of it
其结果
Almost sat on the tiger bench
差点坐到老虎凳上
alright
好吧
Let's not have fun talking about it.
我们不要开玩笑地谈论它。
ok
好的
I ask you
我问你
Did you think of me
你有没有想我
Miss you
想你
think
思考
Especially want to
特别想要
Then if you want me, let's take a shower together.
那如果你愿意的话，我们一起去洗澡吧。
gone
消失了
bath
洗澡
Why can't I hear anything clearly?
为什么我听不清什么？
The faucet is on
水龙头已打开
Eavesdroppers are most afraid of the sound of water drops
窃听者最怕水滴的声音
Isn't your kid very skilled?
你家孩子不是很能干吗？
Think of a way
想想办法
What's so nice about people taking a shower?
人们洗澡有什么好处？
I'm not interested
我对此不感兴趣
What a clear spring for bathing your feet
多么清澈的泉水，可以用来泡脚
Burn the harp and boil the crane
烧琴煮鹤
Pity
遗憾
Can talk now
现在可以说话了
But still keep your voice down
但还是压低声音
so we
所以我们
now can you tell me
现在你可以告诉我吗
why are you pretending
你为什么要假装
Did you pick me up at the train station?
你去火车站接我吗？
Enjoy the meal
享受一顿
What are you doing?
你在干什么？
stop
停止
Step aside
靠边站
Get out of the way
走开
screw you
去你的
magazine
杂志
Slower
慢点
Bear with it
忍受它
why do you want to save me
你为什么要救我
Then why have you been following me for the past three days?
那你这三天为什么一直跟着我？